Guide to the Western Americana Card Photograph File
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Identified Photographers, circa 1851-1965; Series I; 672
  - Savage, Charles Roscoe (1832-1909)
    - Mormon Temple with its spires under construction, Salt Lake City, Utah, circa 1889; 12.5 x 21.1 cm on mount 13.4 x 21.6 cm (Box 11)
    - Royal Arch, Yucca (Joshua Tree) of the Mojave Desert, California., circa 1892; 10.5 x 15.9 cm on mount 10.8 x 16.5 cm (Box 11)
  - Savage, Charles Roscoe (1832-1909), attributed
    - Studio portrait of Brigham Young (1801-1877), circa 1862; 8.6 x 5.5 cm on mount 10.0 x 6.1 cm (Box 11)
    - Studio portrait of Orrin Porter Rockwell (1813-1878), a Utah pioneer and personal bodyguard to Joseph Smith, Jr., and Brigham Young., circa 1862; 8.6 x 5.5 cm on mount 10.1 x 6.1 cm (Box 11)
  - Scharff, Seward (1894-1986)
    Photographer in Nutley, New Jersey
    - Kanab, Utah, from the hill, 1924; 8.8 x 14.7 cm, unmounted (Box 11)
      Scharff was a traveling salesman for the Federal Adding Machine Company, and later Traveler's Insurance, from Nutley, New Jersey
  - Scripture, John Calvin
    Photographer in Angel's Camp, California
    - Studio portrait of John C. Scribner (born 1821), circa 1877; 9.0 x 5.4 cm on mount 10.3 x 6.3 cm (Box 11)
      Scribner was a Wells Fargo agent, druggist, and merchant in Angel's Camp, California. Scribner and Captain Henry Matthews was responsible for the "Calaveras Skull" hoax at Bald Mountain, California, in 1866
    - Copy photograph of a studio portrait of Captain Henry Matthews (died 1867), circa 1877; 8.8 x 5.4 cm on mount 9.0 x 6.2 cm (Box 11)
      Matthews and John C. Scribner (born 1821) were responsible for the "Calaveras Skull" hoax at Bald Mountain, California in 1866.
      Manuscript on verso signed "E. B. B."
  - Senter, William B.
    Photographer in Navasota, Texas
    - Studio portrait of Mrs. Dodge, circa 1890; 14.1 x 9.8 cm on mount 16.5 x 10.7 cm (Box 11)
  - Shaver, Earnest E.
    Photographer in Chelsea, Michigan
    - Exterior of a grocery store with clerks, dressed meat, and pumpkins, probably in Chelsea, Michigan, circa 1880-1890; 14.2 x 10.1 cm on mount 16.5 x 10.8 cm (Box 11)
  - Shaw, George M. (died 1888)
    - Two men with shovels, "making mud for adobes," probably near San Marcial, New Mexico, circa 1882-1883; 9.5 x 12.3 cm on mount 10.9 x 16.5 cm (Box 11)
  - Shepherd, G. B.
    - Interior of Church of the Divine Paternity, New York, New York, with floral arrangements for the funeral of Horace Greeley, 1872 December 4 (Box 11)
      The church changed its names to the Fourth Universalist Society of New York in 1967
  - Shew, Jacob
    - Studio portrait of Alexander Smith Abernethy (1813-1888), circa 1870; 8.6 x 5.5 cm on mount 10.1 x 6.1 cm (Box 11)
      Abernethy came to Oregon in 1850, and was a member of the second legislative assembly of Washington Territory in 1856 and the Constitutional Convention of 1878
  - Shew, William J.
    - Studio portrait of a soldier, circa 1865; 9.1 x 5.6 cm on mount 10.5 x 6.0 cm (Box 11)
    - Studio portrait of a man, circa 1874-1880; 9.1 x 5.7 cm on mount 10.6 x 6.4 cm (Box 11)
  - Shorr, Ray
    Images from a banquet of the New York City Posse of the Westerners International in New York, New York
    - Joseph P. Peters presenting the Annual Buffalo Award of the New York City Posse of the Westerners International to Lowell Dale Morgan (1914-1971) for the year's best non-fiction book on the American West, 1965 Nov; 20.4 x 25.7 cm, unmounted (Box 11)
      Three photographic prints
    - Alvin Joseph, Archibald Hanna (born 1916), Joseph P. Peters, Peter Decker, Lowell Dale Morgan (1914-1971), and Jane Durgin, 1965 Nov; 20.4 x 25.7 cm, unmounted (Box 11)
    - Archibald Hanna (born 1916) reading a speech with Joseph P. Peters and Lowell Dale Morgan (1914-1971), 1965 Nov; 20.4 x 25.7 cm, unmounted (Box 11)
  - Silvis, John B. (1830-1900)
    Traveling photographer in Nebraska and Utah, he operated the Pacific Railroad Photograph Car headquartered in Omaha, Nebraska, and was the official photographer for the Union Pacific Railroad
    - Man on horseback, circa 1870-1882; 6.1 x 9.3 cm on mount 6.3 x 10.6 cm (Box 11)
  - Slater, Edward P. (born 1843)
    Photographer in Ontario, California
    - Euclid Avenue, Ontario, California, circa 1895; 11.5 x 19.5 cm on mount 13.3 x 21.5 cm (Box 11)
  - Slocum, John E. (born 1851)
    - Juana de Dios Machado Wrighton (1814-1901) and cactus hedge, San Diego, California, 1894; 11.5 x 19.1 cm on mount 13.3 x 21.5 cm (Box 11)
    - Juana de Dios Machado Wrighton (1814-1901) at her house, San Diego, California, 1894; 11.7 x 19.6 cm on mount 13.3 x 21.6 cm (Box 11)
    - Interior of the residence of Ulysses S. "Buck" Grant, Jr. (1852-1929), San Diego, California, circa 1895; 11.6 x 19.2 cm on mount 13.3 x 21.6 cm (Box 11)
  - Smith, James Girard (born 1836)
    Photographer in Vallejo, California
    - Studio portrait of a woman, circa 1880; 9.5 x 5.6 cm on mount 9.8 x 5.9 cm (Box 11)
  - Smith, Francis A. (1830-1903)
    Photographer in Salem, Oregon
    - Postmortem portrait of a man, possibly Owen Jasper Ramsey, circa 1869-1881; 4.8 x 9.4 cm on mount 6.4 x 10.6 cm (Box 11)
  - Sohon, Gustave (born 1827)
    - Studio portrait of Reverend Peter John DeSmet (1801-1873), 1863-1864; 8.6 x 5.5 cm on mount 10.1 x 6.1 cm (Box 11)
  - Spalt, F. R.
    Photographer in Wahpeton, Dakota Territory
    - Train of the Northern Pacific Railroad at the depot in Wahpeton, North Dakota, circa 1879; 11.5 x 20.0 cm on mount 13.5 x 21.8 cm (Box 11)
  - Spencer, George E.
    - Copy photograph of a studio portrait of Sitting Bull (1834?-1890), Dakota Indian, 1893; 13.9 x 9.9 cm on mount 16.5 x 10.8 cm (Box 11)
      Original images by David F. Barry (1854-1934), circa 1886
    - Studio portrait of Rain in the Face (circa 1835-1905) with headdress, Dakota Indian, 1893; 14.0 x 9.8 cm on mount 16.5 x 10.8 cm (Box 11)
    - Studio portrait of Rain in the Face (circa 1835-1905), Dakota Indian, 1893; 14.0 x 9.4 cm on mount 16.5 x 10.8 cm (Box 11)
  - Spooner, John Pitcher (1845-1917)
    Photographer in Stockton, California
    - Studio portrait of Charles David Maria Weber (1814-1881), a founder of Stockton, California, 1880; 14.8 x 10.0 cm on mount 22.9 x 15.2 cm (Box 11)
  - Sproule, George B. (born 1852)
    Photographer in Helena, Montana
    - Studio portrait of James M. Croft, Lieutenant, 1st Montana Volunteer Infantry, Company I, circa 1888; 14.1 x 9.9 cm on mount 18.7 x 13.3 cm (Box 11)
      Manuscript on verso: "With my love to my little ones"
  - Stair, Lawrence E. (born 1858)
    Photographer in Mitchell, South Dakota
    - Studio portrait of Running Bull, also known as Ta-tanka Inyanka (born 1834), a Yankton Sioux Indian, circa 1890; 14.0 x 10.0 cm on mount 16.4 x 10.7 cm (Box 11)
      Newspaper clipping about Running Bull pasted on verso
  - Steele & Company
    Photographer in Winnipeg, Manitoba
    - Studio portrait of a man, circa 1893; 14.1 x 9.8 cm on mount 16.3 x 10.7 cm (Box 11)
  - Stewart, George D.
    Photographer in Sacramento, California
    - Houses and farms in a valley, circa 1893; 19.5 x 24.4 cm on mount 20.2 x 25.7 cm (Box 11)
  - Stormer, Henry W. (born 1862)
    - Manitou Springs, Colorado, circa 1885; 10.9 x 17.0 cm on mount 11.4 x 17.8 cm (Box 11)
      Tourist information about Manitou on verso
  - Struckman, Frank (born 1857)
    Photographer in Boise, Idaho
    - Studio portrait of a seated man and standing woman, identified on verso as M. A. Douglass, circa 1888; 14.6 x 10.2 cm on mount 16.5 x 10.7 cm (Box 11)
  - Sturtevant, Joseph Bevier (1851-1910)
    Photographer in Boulder, Colorado
    - Self-portrait of Joseph Bevier Sturtevant (1851-1910), 1908; 14.1 x 10.2 cm on mount 22.8 x 15.2 cm (Box 11)
      Typescript caption on verso includes brief biographical sketch of Sturtevant
  - Sutterley, Clement, and J. K. Sutterley
    Photographers in Virginia City, Nevada
    - Studio portrait of Chief Winnemucca, chief of the Paiute Indians, circa 1870; 9 x 5.5 cm on mount 9.1 x 6.1 cm (Box 11)
    - Studio portrait of a man, circa 1876; 9.6 x 5.6 cm on mount 10.1 x 6.2 cm (Box 11)
  - Swart, John S. (born 1835)
    Photographer in Nevada City, California
    - View of Nevada City, California, circa 1886; 12.0 x 19.7 cm on mount 13.3 x 21.5 cm (Box 11)
  - Taber, Isaiah West (1830-1912)
    - Hotel del Monte, Monterey, California, circa 1880; 12.4 x 20.4 cm on mount 13.6 x 21.5 cm (Box 12)
    - View of San Francisco Bay and Alcatraz Island, California, circa 1880; 12.4 x 20.4 cm on mount 13.6 x 21.4 cm (Box 12)
    - The Golden Gate, and Black Point, San Francisco, California, circa 1880; 12.1 x 20.1 cm on mount 13.7 x 21.3 cm (Box 12)
    - Sierra Madre Villa Hotel, Pasadena, California, circa 1880; 12.5 x 20.2 cm on mount 13.3 x 21.4 cm (Box 12)
    - In a Chinese Restaurant, Washington Street, San Francisco, California, circa 1885; 12.3 x 20.2 cm on mount 13.3 x 21.5 cm (Box 12)
    - Change barn No. 1 of the Mount Hamilton Stage Company, Lick Observatory Road, Mount Hamilton in San Jose, California, circa 1885; 20.1 x 24.5 cm on mount 20.2 x 25.3 cm (Box 12)
    - Grand Dining Room of the Chinese Restaurant, Washington Street, San Francisco, California, circa 1885; 12.5 x 20.2 cm on mount 13.3 x 21.5 cm (Box 12)
    - Studio portrait of John Bidwell (1819-1900), circa 1885; 14.0 x 9.9 cm on mount 16.4 x 10.7 cm (Box 12)
    - Old Pacific Hotel Adobe, Monterey, California, circa 1885; 12.3 x 19.5 cm, unmounted (Box 12)
    - Chinese Butcher and Grocery Shop, Chinatown, San Francisco, California, circa 1885; 12.4 x 20.1 cm on mount 12.9 x 21.5 cm (Box 12)
    - Old adobe building at Monterey, California, circa 1885; 12.3 x 20.3 cm on mount 13.6 x 21.5 cm (Box 12)
      Building occupied by soldiers of General John Charles Frémont during the Mexican War
    - Provision Market in Alley in Chinatown, San Francisco, California, circa 1885; 12.4 x 20.2 cm on mount 13.3 x 21.5 cm (Box 12)
    - Big trees, Felton, Santa Cruz County, California, circa 1895; 12.5 x 20.2 cm on mount 13.3 x 21.4 cm (Box 12)
  - Taber, Isaiah West, and Thomas Henry Boyd
    - Studio portrait of Alphonse Müllender (born circa 1853), industrialist and governmental representative of Belgium, 1874; 10.4 x 15.4 cm on mount 10.8 x 16.5 cm (Box 12)
  - Teal, L.
    L. Teal was a photographer with the United States Army
    - Harrison H. Hightower, Jr., receiving the Military Traffic Management and Service Award from Brigadier General Orvil Cranfill Metheny at the Oakland Army Base, California, 1973 September 12; 20.6 x 25.3 cm, unmounted (Box 12)
  - Thomas, Jessie E. (1859-1928)
    Photographer in Cheney, Washington
    - Studio portrait of Cushing Eells (1810-1893), circa 1890; 9.9 x 5.8 cm on mount 10.6 x 6.3 cm (Box 12)
  - Thompson, T. A.
    - Silver Plume and mines, Colorado, Colorado Central Railroad, circa 1892-1893; 10.8 x 18.4 cm on mount 12.6 x 20.2 cm (Box 12)
  - Thwaites, Joseph (born 1838)
    - Studio portrait of Jean Baptiste Abraham Brouillet (1813-1884), 1886-1896; 14.5 x 10.3 cm on mount 16.5 x 10.8 cm (Box 12)
    - Studio portrait of Modeste Demers (1809-1871), the first Roman Catholic Bishop of Vancouver Island, 1886-1896; 14.5 x 10.2 cm on mount 16.5 x 10.8 cm (Box 12)
  - Tolman, Thomas W.
    Photographer in Nebraska City, Nebraska
    - Pontoon Bridge, Nebraska City, Nebraska, 1884-1885; 7.0 x 18.0 cm on mount 7.3 x 18.0 cm (Box 12)
  - Towne, Bertram C.
    - Mount Hood, Oregon, 1888-1895; 11.0 x 19.6 cm on mount 12.1 x 19.9 cm (Box 12)
    - The Crater, Mount Hood, Oregon, 1888-1895; 11.3 x 19.5 cm on mount 12.1 x 19.7 cm (Box 12)
    - Summit of Mount Hood, Oregon, 1892 August 23? (Box 12)
      Group portrait of a boy, four women, and nine men on the top of Mount Hood, Oregon, after an ascent from August 15-23, 1892. The portrait includes Frederick A. Walpole, a lithographer in Portland, Oregon.
      A brief account of the ascent appears in Earl Morse Wilbur, "An Ascent of Mount Hood," Outing, Volume 24 (August 1894): 348-353
      Image number 1617
      Ink stamp on verso: Stuart & Thompson, Booksellers & Stationers, No. 105 First Street, Portland, Oregon
  - Trager, George (1861-1948)
    - Studio portrait of Chief Red Cloud (1821-1909), Lakota Indian, 1890-1891; 14.1 x 10.0 cm on mount 16.4 x 10.8 cm (Box 12)
      Advertisement on verso for a cure for epilepsy: water from "the famous Minne Pazuta Springs." Probably by George Trager
    - Studio portrait of Herbert J. Zitkalazi (Yellow Bird), the son of Yellow Bird, a Dakota Indian boy and survivor of the Wounded Knee Massacre, South Dakota, 1891; 14.2 x 10.0 cm on mount 16.4 x 10.7 cm (Box 12)
      Probably by George Trager
  - Train, Edgar Horace (1831-1899)
    - Studio portrait of Granville Stuart (1834-1918), a pioneer Montana miner and cattleman, 1868; 7.9 x 5.6 cm on mount 10.1 x 6.2 cm (Box 12)
      Signed "Respectfully yours" by Stuart
  - Turner, E. Winslow
    - Fifth Street, looking south, San Diego, California, circa 1894; 18.8 x 10.9 cm on mount 21.6 x 13.3 cm (Box 12)
  - Upton, Benjamin Franklin (born 1818)
    Photographer in Saint Anthony, Minnesota
    - Winslow House Hotel, Saint Anthony, Minnesota, circa 1862-1863; Oval 5.7 x 7.0 cm on mount 6.2 x 10.7 cm (Box 12)
    - Castle Rock in Dakota County, Minnesota, circa 1865; 8.4 x 5.7 cm on mount 10.3 x 6.0 cm (Box 12)
    - Red River carts of Métis people of mixed American Indian and European ancestry, on their way to Saint Paul, Minnesota; a distance of six hundred miles from Pembina, at Saint Anthony, Minnesota, circa 1870; 5.5 x 7.9 cm on mount 6.6 x 10.1 cm (Box 12)
  - Urwiller, John F.
    - Teller House, Central City, Colorado, 1948; 25.3 x 20.6 cm, unmounted (Box 12)
    - A view of Central City, Colorado, from the hills, 1948; 20.7 x 25.4 cm, unmounted (Box 12)
    - Central City, Colorado, street scene, 1948; 20.6 x 25.4 cm, unmounted (Box 12)
  - Vaughan, John William
    Photographer in Victoria, British Columbia
    - Studio portrait of George A. Paige (died 1868), Indian Agent at Port Madison, 1862-1865; 9.4 x 5.7 cm on mount 10.3 x 6.1 cm (Box 12)
  - Vaupel, Herman M.
    - Studio portrait of Alex Stein, a rifle marksman and member of the 7th Regiment of New York City, New York State Militia, circa 1889; 15.1 x 10.0 cm on mount 16.5 x 10.7 cm (Box 12)
  - Wantz, James
    - Corbin Gulch along the Montana Central Railroad From Helena to Butte, circa 1887; 11.6 x 18.9 cm on mount 12.6 x 20.3 cm (Box 12)
      A railroad bridge spanning a Gulch
  - Ward, Thomas Chester
    Photographer in Roseburg, Oregon
    - Men in front of Masonic temple, Athena, Oregon, 1889; 13.8 x 21.1 cm on mount 17.6 x 25.3 cm (Box 12)
  - Washburn, Beverly Ansley (circa 1900-1952)
    - View of a touring car manufactured by the Maxwell Motor Company in 1916 with a view of San Francisco Bay in the background, circa 1920; 19.3 x 25.3 cm, unmounted (Box 12)
      Purchased from the William Reese Company on the Frederick W. and Carrie S. Beinecke Fund for Western Americana, 2010
    - View of a touring car inside a building, circa 1920; 20.3 x 25.3 cm, unmounted (Box 12)
  - Watkins, Carleton E. (1829-1916)
    - The Father of the Forest, four hundred and fifty feet high, forty feet in diameter, Mammoth Tree Grove, Calaveras County, California, 1880-1888; 12.1 x 20.9 cm on mount 13.7 x 21.4 cm (Box 12)
    - Palace Hotel, San Francisco, California, circa 1875; 12.0 x 20.7 cm on mount 13.7 x 21.4 cm (Box 12)
    - Palace Hotel, Market Street and Front, San Francisco, California, circa 1875; 8.4 x 15.3 cm on mount 10.7 x 16.5 cm (Box 12)
    - Grand Hotel, Market Street and New Montgomery Street, San Francisco, California, circa 1875; 7.4 x 11.7 cm on mount 8.2 x 12.7 cm (Box 12)
    - The Sentinel, 3270 Feet, Yosemite National Park, California, circa 1875; 19.8 x 12.2 cm on mount 21.3 x 13.7 cm (Box 12)
    - Lick House, New Montgomery Street, San Francisco, California, circa 1875; 7.0 x 11.4 cm on mount 8.2 x 12.7 cm (Box 12)
  - Watkins, Carleton E., 1829-1916, attributed
    - Interior Consolidated Virginia Pan Mill, Virginia City, Nevada, circa 1880; 9.2 x 15.5 cm on mount 11.5 x 18.4 cm (Box 12)
    - Interior view of the California Pan Mill, Virginia City, Nevada, circa 1880; 9.3 x 15.3 cm on mount 11.5 x 18.4 cm (Box 12)
  - Way & Knoerzer
    Photographer in Leavenworth, Kansas; partnership of Thomas Knoerzer and Way
    - Storefront of a hardware store, circa 1900; 10.1 x 13.8 cm on mount 10.8 x 16.5 cm (Box 12)
  - Weary, Milton, and Allie Weary
    Photographers in Lanark, Illinois
    - Studio portrait of a woman, circa 1880; 9.1 x 5.7 cm on mount 10.5 x 6.3 cm (Box 12)
  - Webster, Fred A. (born 1861)
    - Studio portrait of an infant comprised of three exposures, circa 1900; 9.8 x 14 cm on mount 10.8 x 16.5 cm (Box 12)
  - Weitz, Hugo
    Photographer in Fruitvale and San Francisco, California
    - Group of children, possibly a class portrait, 1910; 11.5 x 19 cm on mount 17.6 x 25 cm (Box 13)
    - Group of children, possibly a class portrait at a school in Oakland, California, 1911; 11.5 x 19 cm on mount 17.6 x 25 cm (Box 13)
    - Group of children, possibly a class portrait at a school in Oakland, California, 1912; 11.5 x 19 cm on mount 17.6 x 25 cm (Box 13)
    - Group of basketball players, 1913; 11.5 x 19.4 cm on mount 17.6 x 25 cm (Box 13)
    - Group of children, possibly a class portrait, circa 1884-1888; 10.4 x 18.3 cm on mount 18.5 x 23.6 cm (Box 13)
  - Werner & Kern
    - Studio portrait of John W. "Captain Jack" Crawford (1847-1917), circa 1885; 13.8 x 9.5 cm on mount 16.5 x 10.8 cm (Box 13)
      Manuscript poem on verso addressed to "Capt. Jn. L Bullis" and signed by "Jack Crawford, a Poet Scout"
    - Studio portrait of John W. "Captain Jack" Crawford (1847-1917), circa 1885; 13.8 x 9.4 cm on mount 16.5 x 10.8 cm (Box 13)
  - Wesner, H. B.
    Photographer in San Bernardino, California
    - Santa Fe Railroad in Cajon Pass, California, circa 1890; 11.6 x 18.9 cm on mount 13.3 x 21.6 cm (Box 13)
    - Snowcapped mountains, San Bernardino, California with Redlands in foreground, circa 1890; 11.5 x 19.0 cm on mount 13.3 x 21.6 cm (Box 13)
  - Whitney & Son
    Photography studio in Cambridgeport, Massachusetts
    - Studio portrait of George Graham Spurr (born 1827), member of the New England Associated California Pioneers of 1849, 1896; 14.2 x 9.9 cm on mount 16.0 x 10.9 cm (Box 13)
      Manuscript inscription on verso from Spurr to George W. Meacham "In memory of many a storm we endured off Cape Horn way back in '49"
  - Whitney, Joel Emmons (1822-1886)
    Photographer in Saint Paul, Minnesota
    - Studio portrait of Anpetu-Tokeca (1819-1869), also known as Anpetutokeca or John Other Day, a Wahpeton Dakota Indian, circa 1862; 8.3 x 5.8 cm on mount 10.2 x 6.1 cm (Box 13)
      Purchased from the William Reese Company (Cowan's sale, 2009 December 9, lot 239) on the Walter McClintock Memorial Fund, 2010
    - Studio portrait of U-Se-Do-Ha, a Mdewakanton Indian woman, circa 1862; 8.3 x 5.8 cm on mount 9.4 x 6.2 cm (Box 13)
      United States Internal Revenue stamp affixed to the recto of the mount
    - Portrait of two women, probably Mdewakanton Indians, circa 1862; 8.2 x 5.4 cm on mount 9.5 x 6.1 cm (Box 13)
    - Portrait of Ma-Za-Oo-Nie, also known as The Little Bird Hunter, a Dakota Indian boy, circa 1862; 8.6 x 5.7 cm on mount 10.3 x 6.1 cm (Box 13)
      Purchased from the William Reese Company (Cowan's sale, 2009 December 9, lot 305) on the Walter McClintock Memorial Fund, 2010
    - Studio portrait of Little Hill, a chief of the Winnebago Indians, circa 1865 (Box 13)
    - Suspension bridge over the Mississippi at the Falls of Saint Anthony, Minnesota, circa 1865; 8.0 x 5.8 cm on mount 10.2 x 6.1 cm (Box 13)
  - Whittemore, Frank H. (born 1851) (Box 13)
    Photographer in Hot Springs, South Dakota
  - View of fifteen men and four women posed standing in front of and on the balcony of the Catholicon Hotel and Bathhouse, Hot Springs, South Dakota, circa 1890; 15.5 x 23.6 cm on mount 17.3 x 24.8 cm (Box 13)
  - Whittier, Lauritson G. (born 1854)
    Photographer in Wichita, Kansas
    - Three men in front of a biplane, including John Aason (1887-1938), also known as John Aasen, a circus performer and vaudeville giant, 1922; 19.0 x 24.3 cm, unmounted (Box 13)
      Inscription on verso to "Rev. Jim Russell, B. P. O. Elks" from John Aason
  - Wilse, Anders Beers
    - View of the steamer Humboldt, circa 1898; 18.1 x 23.5 cm on mount 22.7 x 27.8 cm (Box 13)
  - Wilson, W. H. (Box 13)
  - Wiltse, Jerome
    - Corn Palace, Mitchell, South Dakota, 1893; 11.6 x 18.6 cm on mount 12.7 x 20.3 cm (Box 13)
      Advertisement on verso for "J. N. Crow, Real Estate Broker, Mitchell, South Dakota"
  - Winter & Pond
    Photographer in Juneau, Alaska; partnership of Lloyd V. Winter and Percy E. Pond
    - Sitka, Alaska, from Mission Buildings, 1896; 11.2 x 19.2 cm on mount 14.5 x 22.0 cm (Box 13)
  - Wittick, George Benjamin (1845-1903)
    - Cattle Round-Up, White Mountains, Arizona; Apache Indians herding cattle, circa 1881; 19.7 x 11.6 cm on mount 21.7 x 13.4 cm (Box 13)
  - Wolf, Henry L. (1850-1924)
    Photographer in Garden City and Manhattan, Kansas
    - Promotional photomontage of agricultural sites in and around Garden City, Kansas, circa 1890; 12.4 x 18.8 cm on mount 13.4 x 21.6 cm (Box 13)
      Gift of Michael Vinson, 2010
  - Wolfe, Samuel A.
    - Studio portrait of a man, circa 1880; 9.5 x 5.7 cm on mount 10.4 x 6.4 cm (Box 13)
  - Wood, John
    - Studio portrait of Annie Oakley (1860-1926), circa 1885; 13.7 x 10.1 cm on mount 16.5 x 10.7 cm (Box 13)
      Letterpress caption on verso describes Oakley's sharpshooting abilities
    - Studio portrait of Annie Oakley (1860-1926) standing with rifles, circa 1885; 14.3 x 10.2 cm on mount 16.5 x 10.7 cm (Box 13)
  - Woodard, Alonzo Bixby (1840-1918)
    - McCaffrey's Presbyterian Church, Portland, Oregon, 1864-1865; 8.6 x 5.6 cm on mount 10.1 x 6.1 cm (Box 13)
  - Woodcock, William Percy (1888-1957)
    - Studio portrait of Cornelius Cole (1822-1924), 16.5 x 11.7 cm on mount 26.6 x 19.0 cm (Box 13)
      Cornelius Cole (1822-1924) United States House of Representative for California from 1863 to 1865 and in the United States Senate from 1867 to 1873
  - Worden, Isaac D. (born 1870)
    Photographer in Mandan, North Dakota; Worden was a conductor with the Northern Pacific Railroad Company
    - Snowbound Northern Pacific train, one-half mile west of Elliott, North Dakota, 1896-1897; 19.9 x 29.9 cm on mount 19.9 x 29.9 cm (Box 13)
      Manuscript inscription on verso and an anonymous letter accompanying the photograph details a brakeman's railroad career, circa 1880-1889
  - Wright, Charles C.
    - Studio portrait of a man posed standing next to a penny-farthing bicycle, also known as a high wheel, high wheeler, and ordinary bicycle, circa 1885; 14.6 x 10.2 cm on mount 16.6 x 10.9 cm (Box 13)
  - Zimmerman, Charles Alfred (1844-1909)
    - Studio portrait of Charles Lamborn, a western land commissioner and agent for the Northern Pacific Railroad Company, circa 1885; 14.1 x 9.8 cm on mount 16.6 x 10.9 cm (Box 13)
    - Studio portrait of Dr. Nicholas Rowe (1842-1896), editor of American Field Journal, circa 1895; 14.5 x 10.0 cm on mount 16.1 x 10.7 cm (Box 13)
      Signed "yrs. respectfully, N Rowe" on verso
- Unidentified Photographers, circa 1850-circa 1951; Series II; 359
  This series consists of photographic prints and their accompanying mounts that have dimensions less than 22 x 29 cm (8.7 x 11.4 in.) in size and created by unidentified photographers. Materials with larger dimensions are located in Series III. Oversize.
  Photographs in this series are organized into two subseries: Identified Locations and Portraits.
  - Identified Locations